So you probably have the sense, as most people do,
ربما لديكم الشعور، كَمُعظَم الناس،
that polarization is getting worse in our country,
بأن القطبية تزداد سوءًا في بلادنا،
that the divide between the left and the right
بأن الانقسام بين اليسار واليمين
is as bad as it's been in really any of our lifetimes.
أسوأ مما كان عليه في أي فترة من حياتنا
But you might also reasonably wonder if research backs up your intuition.
لكنكم أيضًا قد تتساءلون بعقلانية إن كانت البحوث تدعم حدسكم
And in a nutshell, the answer is sadly yes.
وباختصار، الجواب للأسف هو نعم.
In study after study, we find
بِدراسَة تلو الأخرى، نجد
that liberals and conservatives have grown further apart.
أن الليبراليين والمحافظين أصبحوا أكثر فُرقَة.
They increasingly wall themselves off in these ideological silos,
إنهم يعزلون أنفسهم بشكلٍ متزايد في هذه الصوامع الإيديولوجية،
consuming different news, talking only to like-minded others
يعالجون أخبار مختلفة، يتحدثون فقط للمشابهين لهم فكريًا
and more and more choosing to live in different parts of the country.
وأكثر فأكثر، يختارون العيش في أجزاء مختلفة من الدولة.
And I think that most alarming of all of it
وأعتقد أنه أكثر ما يثير القلق في ذلك
is seeing this rising animosity on both sides.
هو رؤية هذا العداء المتصاعد على كلا الجانبين.
Liberals and conservatives,
ليبراليون ومحافظون،
Democrats and Republicans,
ديموقراطيون وجمهوريون،
more and more they just don't like one another.
والمزيد والمزيد، إنهم فقط لا يحبون بعضهم البعض.
You see it in many different ways.
يمكنكم رؤية ذلك بعدة طرق مختلفة.
They don't want to befriend one another. They don't want to date one another.
إنهم لا يريدون مصداقة بعضهم البعض. لا يريدون مواعدة بعضهم البعض.
If they do, if they find out, they find each other less attractive,
لو فعلوا، واكتشفوا الأمر، يجدون بعضهم أقل جاذبية.
and they more and more don't want their children to marry someone
وأكثر فأكثر، فهم لا يريدون أن يتزوج أولادهم
who supports the other party,
بمن يساند الحزب الآخر،
a particularly shocking statistic.
إحصائية صادمة فعلًا.
You know, in my lab, the students that I work with,
تعلمون، في مختبري، الطلاب الذين أعمل معهم،
we're talking about some sort of social pattern --
نتحدث عن بعض أنواع الأنماط الإجتماعية --
I'm a movie buff, and so I'm often like,
أنا مولعٌ بالأفلام، ولذلك غالبًا ما أقول،
what kind of movie are we in here with this pattern?
ما هي نوعية الفيلم الذي نحن فيه بهذا النمط؟
So what kind of movie are we in with political polarization?
وبالتالي ما هي نوعية الفيلم الذي نحن فيه بهذه القطبية السياسية؟
Well, it could be a disaster movie.
حسنًا، قد يكون فيلماً كارثياً.
It certainly seems like a disaster.
إنه يبدو ككارثة حقًا.
Could be a war movie.
قد يكون فيلماً حربياً.
Also fits.
ملائم أيضًا.
But what I keep thinking is that we're in a zombie apocalypse movie.
لكن ما أواصل التفكير به أننا في فيلم "نهاية عالم الزومبي".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Right? You know the kind.
صحيح؟ تعرفون هذا النوع.
There's people wandering around in packs,
هناك أشخاص يتجولون في الأنحاء في جماعات،
not thinking for themselves,
لا يفكرون بأنفسهم،
seized by this mob mentality
استولت عليهم عقلية الغوغاء
trying to spread their disease and destroy society.
يحاولون نشر أمراضهم وتدمير المجتمع.
And you probably think, as I do,
وغالبًا أنك تظن، كما أنا أظن،
that you're the good guy in the zombie apocalypse movie,
أنك الشخص الجيد في فيلم نهاية عالم الزومبي،
and all this hate and polarization, it's being propagated by the other people,
وأن كل هذا الكره والتباعد، يجري نشره من قِبَل أشخاص آخرين،
because we're Brad Pitt, right?
لأننا براد بيت، أليس كذلك؟
Free-thinking, righteous,
مفكرون أحرار، صالحون،
just trying to hold on to what we hold dear,
نحاول فقط التمسك بما هو عزيز علينا،
you know, not foot soldiers in the army of the undead.
كما تعلمون، لسنا جنود مشاة في جيش الموتى الأحياء.
Not that.
ليس هذا.
Never that.
أبدًا.
But here's the thing:
ولكن هذا هو الأمر:
what movie do you suppose they think they're in?
ما هو الفيلم الذي تظنون أنهم يعتقدون أنفسهم فيه؟
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
Well, they absolutely think that they're the good guys
حسنًا، أنهم بلا شك يعتقدون أنهم هم الأخيار
in the zombie apocalypse movie. Right?
في فيلم نهاية عالم الزومبي. صحيح؟
And you'd better believe that they think that they're Brad Pitt
ومن الأفضل لك أن تعتقد أنهم يحسبون أنفسهم براد بيت
and that we, we are the zombies.
وأننا، نحن الزومبي.
And who's to say that they're wrong?
ومن الذي يقول أنهم على خطأ؟
I think that the truth is that we're all a part of this.
أعتقد أن الحقيقة هي أننا جميعًا جزء من هذا.
And the good side of that is that we can be a part of the solution.
والشيء الجيد في ذلك أننا يمكن أن نكون جزءًا من الحل.
So what are we going to do?
إذن ماذا سنفعل؟
What can we do to chip away at polarization in everyday life?
ما الذي يمكننا فعله لتقليص التباعد في حياتنا اليومية؟
What could we do to connect with and communicate with
ماذا يمكن أن نفعله للاتصال والتواصل مع
our political counterparts?
نظرائنا السياسيين؟
Well, these were exactly the questions that I and my colleague, Matt Feinberg,
حسنًا، هذه كانت نفس الأسئلة التي أصبحنا أنا وزميلي، مات فينبيرغ،
became fascinated with a few years ago,
مولعين بها منذ بضع سنوات،
and we started doing research on this topic.
وبدأنا بإجراء بحث حول هذا الموضوع.
And one of the first things that we discovered
ومن أول الأشياء التي اكتشفناها،
that I think is really helpful for understanding polarization
أنني أعتقد أنه من المفيد حقًا في فهم القطبية
is to understand
هو فهم
that the political divide in our country is undergirded by a deeper moral divide.
أنّ الانقسام السياسي في بلدنا مدعوم بانقسامٍ أخلاقيٍ أعمق.
So one of the most robust findings in the history of political psychology
ولذلك واحدة من أقوى النتائج في تاريخ علم النفس السياسي
is this pattern identified by Jon Haidt and Jesse Graham,
هذا النموذج الذي حُدد عن طريق جون هايت وجيسي غراهام،
psychologists,
علماء نفسيون،
that liberals and conservatives tend to endorse different values
أنّ الليبراليين والمحافظين يميلون لتأييد قيم مختلفة
to different degrees.
بدرجات مختلفة.
So for example, we find that liberals tend to endorse values like equality
على سبيل المثال، نجد الليبراليين يميلون لتأييد قيم كالمساواة
and fairness and care and protection from harm
والعدل والرعاية والحماية من الضرر
more than conservatives do.
أكثر مما يفعل المحافظون.
And conservatives tend to endorse values like loyalty, patriotism,
والمحافظون يميلون إلى تأييد قيم كالولاء والوطنية
respect for authority and moral purity
واحترام السلطات والنقاء الأخلاقي
more than liberals do.
أكثر مما يفعل الليبراليون.
And Matt and I were thinking that maybe this moral divide
أنا ومات كنّا نفكر أنه ربما يكون هذا الانقسام الأخلاقي
might be helpful for understanding how it is
مفيدًا في فهم الكيفية
that liberals and conservatives talk to one another
التي يتحدث بها الليبراليون والمحافظون لبعضهم البعض
and why they so often seem to talk past one another
ولماذا غالبًا ما يبدو أنهم يتحدثون عن شيءٍ مختلف
when they do.
عندما يتحدثون.
So we conducted a study
ولذلك قمنا بإجراء دراسة
where we recruited liberals to a study
حيث قمنا بالاستعانة ببعض الليبراليين لإجراء دراسة
where they were supposed to write a persuasive essay
حيث كان من المفترض أن يقوموا بكتابة مقال إقناعي
that would be compelling to a conservative in support of same-sex marriage.
يكون مقنعًا لشخص محافظ لدعم زواج المثليين.
And what we found was that liberals tended to make arguments
وما وجدناه هو أن الليبراليين يميلون لبناء حججهم
in terms of the liberal moral values of equality and fairness.
من خلال القيم الأخلاقية الليبرالية، عن العدل والمساواة.
So they said things like,
ولذلك قالوا أشياء مثل،
"Everyone should have the right to love whoever they choose,"
"يجب أن يكون لكل شخص الحق في حب أي شخص يختاره"
and, "They" -- they being gay Americans --
و"هم -- كونهم مثليين أمريكيين--
"deserve the same equal rights as other Americans."
يستحقون نفس المساواة بالحقوق كالأمريكين الآخرين."
Overall, we found that 69 percent of liberals
بصورة شاملة، وجدنا أن 96% من الليبراليين
invoked one of the more liberal moral values in constructing their essay,
استندوا إلى واحدة أو أكثر من قيمهم الأخلاقية في بناء مقالاتهم.
and only nine percent invoked one of the more conservative moral values,
و9% فقط استندوا إلى واحدة أو أكثر من قيم المحافظيين الأخلاقية،
even though they were supposed to be trying to persuade conservatives.
برغم أنهم من المفترض أن يحاولوا إقناع المحافظين.
And when we studied conservatives and had them make persuasive arguments
وعندما قمنا بدراسة المحافظين وجعلناهم يقوموا بكتابة حجج إقناعية
in support of making English the official language of the US,
لدعم اللغة الإنجليزية كاللغة الرسمية للولايات المتحدة،
a classically conservative political position,
موقف سياسي تقليدي محافظ،
we found that they weren't much better at this.
لم نجدهم أفضل بكثير.
59 percent of them made arguments
59% منهم بنوا حججهم
in terms of one of the more conservative moral values,
على واحدة أو أكثر من قيم المحافظين الأخلاقية
and just eight percent invoked a liberal moral value,
و8% فقط استندوا إلى قيم الليبراليين الأخلاقية.
even though they were supposed to be targeting liberals for persuasion.
بالرغم من أنه كان من المفترض أن يستهدفوا الليبراليين بالإقناع.
Now, you can see right away why we're in trouble here. Right?
الآن، يمكنك أن ترى لم نحن في مشكلة هنا، أليس كذلك؟
People's moral values, they're their most deeply held beliefs.
قيم الناس الأخلاقية، إنها أعمق المعتقدات.
People are willing to fight and die for their values.
الناس على استعداد للقتال والموت من أجل قيمهم الأخلاقية.
Why are they going to give that up just to agree with you
لماذا عليهم التخلي عن كل ذلك للاتفاق معك
on something that they don't particularly want to agree with you on anyway?
على شيء هم لا يريدون تحديدًا الاتفاق معك فيه على أية حال؟
If that persuasive appeal that you're making to your Republican uncle
إذا كان الطلب المُقْنِع الذي تقدمه إلى عمك الجمهوري
means that he doesn't just have to change his view,
يعني أنه ليس عليه فقط تغيير رأيه،
he's got to change his underlying values, too,
ولكن عليه تغيير قيمه الأساسية أيضًا،
that's not going to go very far.
إن هذا لن يجدي نفعًا.
So what would work better?
إذن ما هي الطريقة الأفضل؟
Well, we believe it's a technique that we call moral reframing,
حسنًا، نحن نعتقد أنه أسلوب نطلق عليه إعادة الصياغة الأخلاقية،
and we've studied it in a series of experiments.
وقمنا بدارستها في سلسلة من التجارب.
In one of these experiments,
في إحدى هذه التجارب،
we recruited liberals and conservatives to a study
استقدمنا ليبراليين ومحافظين لإجراء دراسة
where they read one of three essays
يقومون فيها بقراءة مقالة واحدة من ثلاث مقالات
before having their environmental attitudes surveyed.
قبل استطلاع مواقفهم نحو البيئة.
And the first of these essays
وأول هذه المقالات
was a relatively conventional pro-environmental essay
كان مقالًا تقليديًا مناصرًا للبيئة
that invoked the liberal values of care and protection from harm.
والذي استند إلى قيم الليبراليين عن الرعاية والحماية من الضرر.
It said things like, "In many important ways
تضمن جُملًا مثل، "نحن نسبب ضرراً حقيقياً بطرق مختلفة
we are causing real harm to the places we live in,"
للأماكن التي نعيش بها"
and, "It is essential that we take steps now
و"ومن الضروري الآن أن نتخذ إجراءات
to prevent further destruction from being done to our Earth."
لمنع حدوث مزيد من الدمار لكوكب الأرض."
Another group of participants
مجموعة أخرى من المشاركين
were assigned to read a really different essay
طُلب منهم قراءة مقال مختلف تمامًا
that was designed to tap into the conservative value of moral purity.
والذي كُتب بناءًا على قيم المحافظين عن النقاء الأخلاقي.
It was a pro-environmental essay as well,
وكان مقالًا مناصرًا للبيئة أيضًا،
and it said things like,
وتضمن جُمَل مثل،
"Keeping our forests, drinking water, and skies pure is of vital importance."
"الحفاظ على غاباتنا ومياهنا الصالحة للشرب ونقاء سماءنا، هو أمر ذو أهمية قصوى."
"We should regard the pollution
"يجب علينا أن نعتبر تلوث
of the places we live in to be disgusting."
الأماكن التي نعيش فيها أمرًا مقرفًا."
And, "Reducing pollution can help us preserve
و"الحد من التلوث قد يساعدنا في الحفاظ على
what is pure and beautiful about the places we live."
كل ما هو جميل ونقي في الأماكن التي نعيش فيها."
And then we had a third group
ومن ثم كان لدينا مجموعة ثالثة
that were assigned to read just a nonpolitical essay.
والتي طُلب منها قراءة مقال غير سياسي.
It was just a comparison group so we could get a baseline.
كانت فقط مجموعة لمقارنة النتائج.
And what we found when we surveyed people
وما وجدناه عند استطلاع آرائهم
about their environmental attitudes afterwards,
عن مواقفهم نحو البيئة بعد ذلك،
we found that liberals, it didn't matter what essay they read.
وجدنا أن الليبراليين، لا يهم أي مقال قرأوا.
They tended to have highly pro-environmental attitudes regardless.
إنهم بغض النظر يميلون لامتلاك مواقف قوية مناصرة للبيئة.
Liberals are on board for environmental protection.
الليبراليون من الداعمين لحماية البيئة.
Conservatives, however,
والمحافظون، على أية حال،
were significantly more supportive of progressive environmental policies
كانوا إلى حد كبير أكثر دعمًا للسياسات البيئية
and environmental protection
وحماية البيئة
if they had read the moral purity essay
عند قراءة المقال الذي تضمن النقاء الأخلاقي
than if they read one of the other two essays.
مما لو قرأوا أحد المقالين الأخرين.
We even found that conservatives who read the moral purity essay
وجدنا أن المحافظين الذين قرأوا مقال النقاء الأخلاقي
were significantly more likely to say that they believed in global warming
كانوا إلى حد كبير أكثر قابلية لقول أنهم يؤمنون بظاهرة الاحتباس الحراري
and were concerned about global warming,
وأنهم قلقون تجاه الاحتباس الحراري،
even though this essay didn't even mention global warming.
على الرغم من أن هذا المقال لم يذكر حتى الاحتباس الحراري.
That's just a related environmental issue.
إنه مجرد قضية بيئية ذات صلة.
But that's how robust this moral reframing effect was.
ولكن هذا يوضح مدى قوة وتأثير إعادة الصياغة الأخلاقية.
And we've studied this on a whole slew of different political issues.
ولقد درسنا هذا على مجموعة كاملة من القضايا السياسية المختلفة.
So if you want to move conservatives
ولذلك إن كنت تريد إقناع المحافظين
on issues like same-sex marriage or national health insurance,
بقضايا مثل زواج المثليين أو التأمين الصحي القومي،
it helps to tie these liberal political issues to conservative values
فإنه من الأفضل ربط هذه القضايا السياسية الليبرالية بقيم المحافظين
like patriotism and moral purity.
مثل الوطنية والنقاء الأخلاقي.
And we studied it the other way, too.
ودرسنا الوضع المعاكس أيضًا.
If you want to move liberals to the right on conservative policy issues
إذا كنت تريد إقناع الليبراليين بقضايا سياسية محافظة
like military spending and making English the official language of the US,
مثل الإنفاق العسكري وجعل اللغة الإنجليزية اللغة الرسمية للولايات المتحدة،
you're going to be more persuasive
ستكون أكثر إقناعًا
if you tie those conservative policy issues to liberal moral values
إن ربطتَ هذه القضايا السياسية المحافظة بقيم الليبراليين الأخلاقية
like equality and fairness.
مثل العدل والمساواة.
All these studies have the same clear message:
جميع هذه الدراسات توصل نفس الرسالة الواضحة:
if you want to persuade someone on some policy,
إن كنت تريد إقناع شخصاً ما بسياسة معينة،
it's helpful to connect that policy to their underlying moral values.
فإنه من المفيد ربط تلك السياسة بالقيم الأخلاقية التي يستند إليها.
And when you say it like that
وعندما تقولها بهذه الطريقة
it seems really obvious. Right?
ستبدو حقًا بديهية. صحيح؟
Like, why did we come here tonight?
مثل، لماذا جئنا إلى هنا الليلة؟
Why --
لماذا --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's incredibly intuitive.
إنه شيء بديهي للغاية.
And even though it is, it's something we really struggle to do.
وبالرغم من أنه كذلك، إنه شيء نناضل من أجل فعله.
You know, it turns out that when we go to persuade somebody on a political issue,
كما تعلمون، فقد اتضح أنه عندما نذهب لإقناع شخص ما بقضية سياسية،
we talk like we're speaking into a mirror.
نتحدث كما لو أننا نتحدث إلى أنفسنا.
We don't persuade so much as we rehearse our own reasons
نحن لا نقنع كثيرًا عندما نقوم بتكرار أفكارنا الخاصة
for why we believe some sort of political position.
لأننا نعتقد أنها نوعًا ما موقفًا سياسيًا.
We kept saying when we were designing these reframed moral arguments,
لقد استمرينا بالقول عندما كنا نصمم هذه الحجج المعاد صياغتها أخلاقيًا،
"Empathy and respect, empathy and respect."
"التعاطف والاحترام، التعاطف والاحترام"
If you can tap into that,
إن استطعت اللعب على هذا الوتر،
you can connect
يمكنك التواصل
and you might be able to persuade somebody in this country.
وقد تكون قادرًا على إقناع شخص ما في هذا البلد.
So thinking again
إذًا بالتفكير مرة أخرى
about what movie we're in,
في ماهية الفيلم الذي نحن فيه،
maybe I got carried away before.
ربما قد أكون تحمست قبل قليل.
Maybe it's not a zombie apocalypse movie.
ربما هو ليس فيلم نهاية عالم الزومبي.
Maybe instead it's a buddy cop movie.
ربما يكون فيلمًا بوليسيًا بدلًا من ذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Just roll with it, just go with it please.
تقبلوا هذا الأمر من فضلكم.
You know the kind: there's a white cop and a black cop,
تعرفون هذا النوع: شرطي أبيض مع شرطي أسود،
or maybe a messy cop and an organized cop.
أو شرطي فوضوي مع شرطي منظم.
Whatever it is, they don't get along
أيًا كان، فإنهم لا يتفقون مع بعضهم
because of this difference.
بسبب هذا الاختلاف.
But in the end, when they have to come together and they cooperate,
لكن في النهاية، عندما يكون عليهم العمل معًا وأن يتعاونوا،
the solidarity that they feel,
التضامن الذي يشعرون به،
it's greater because of that gulf that they had to cross. Right?
يكون أكبر، بسبب العقبات التي كان عليهم تجاوزها. صحيح؟
And remember that in these movies,
وتذكروا أن في هذه الأفلام،
it's usually worst in the second act
أنها عادة ما تكون أسوأ في الفصل الثاني
when our leads are further apart than ever before.
عندما يكون أبطالنا أكثر تباعدًا من أي وقت مضى.
And so maybe that's where we are in this country,
وربما هذا ما نحن عليه في هذا البلد،
late in the second act of a buddy cop movie --
في الجزء الأخير من الفصل الثاني من فيلم بوليسي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
torn apart but about to come back together.
مُفككين ولكن على وشك أن نعود معًا.
It sounds good,
هذا يبدو جيدًا،
but if we want it to happen,
لكن إن كنّا نريد لذلك أن يحدث،
I think the responsibility is going to start with us.
أعتقد أن المسؤولية ستبدأ من عندنا.
So this is my call to you:
لذلك هذا هو ندائي لكم:
let's put this country back together.
دعونا نوحّد هذا البلد من جديد.
Let's do it despite the politicians
دعونا نفعل ذلك رغم السياسيين
and the media and Facebook and Twitter
ووسائل الإعلام و"فيسبوك" و"تويتر"
and Congressional redistricting
وترسيم الدوائر الانتخابية
and all of it, all the things that divide us.
وكل ذلك، كل الأشياء التي تفرق بيننا.
Let's do it because it's right.
لنقم بهذا لأنه صحيح.
And let's do it because this hate and contempt
ولنقم به لأن هذا الكره والاحتقار
that flows through all of us every day
الذي يسري داخلنا كل يوم
makes us ugly and it corrupts us,
يجعلنا قبيحين ويفسدنا،
and it threatens the very fabric of our society.
ويهدد نسيج مجتمعنا.
We owe it to one another and our country
نحن مدينون لبعضنا البعض ولبلدنا
to reach out and try to connect.
بأن نتواصل ونحاول أن نترابط.
We can't afford to hate them any longer,
إننا لا نستطيع أن نكرههم لفترة أطول،
and we can't afford to let them hate us either.
ولا يمكننا السماح لهم بكرهنا أيضًا.
Empathy and respect.
التعاطف والاحترام.
If you think about it, it's the very least that we owe our fellow citizens.
إن فكرتم بهذا، فهو أقل ما ما يتوجب علينا تجاه مواطنينا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)